projectwhois.org 2012-06-04

# Privacy Policy - DomainTools, LLC

_Last updated April 2010_

### Introduction

DomainTools LLC ("DomainTools") (collectively, the "Site") respects and protects the privacy of the individuals that use the Site and our Services. 

The practices of DomainTools with respect to data collected and used in connection with our Site and Services are governed by this online privacy policy ("Privacy Policy"). By accessing our Site and/or using any of our Services, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy and expressly consent to DomainTools’ use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance herewith. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of the DomainTools Terms Of Service. All capitalized terms not otherwise defined herein are defined in the Terms Of Service. 

IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO ALL OF THESE TERMS AND CONDITIONS, THEN DO NOT USE OUR SITE/SERVICES. 

DomainTools may change this Privacy Policy from time to time at its sole discretion. Such changes shall be effective as noted in our Terms Of Service. 

### Personal Information 

Before granting you access to certain functions of our Site or Services, you may be required to provide us with personal information such as your email address, your name, company name, address, and credit-card billing information (the "Registration Information" which makes you a "Registered User") 

Subject to conditions, you will be able to review and change the information you submit to us by accessing your Account and entering the new information yourself. 

It is your responsibility to always maintain your Registration Information complete, accurate and up-to-date. In addition, DomainTools may require that you confirm your Registration Information or certain parts of your Registration Information at any time for any reason. 

Subject to conditions in the Terms Of Service and other restrictions, you may deactivate or delete your Account or the information contained therein. Deactivating or deleting your account can be completed in your Account page. In certain circumstances we may refuse or delay deactivation or deletion. Even if an Account is deactivated or deleted, we will still retain all or some of your information for internal use consistent with this Privacy Policy, or in order to prevent fraud, collect fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms Of Service, and comply with legal requirements. Therefore, you should not expect that your information will be completely removed from our databases in response to your requests. 

Neither our Site nor our Services are designed for or directed to children under the age of 18. If you are under the age of 18, we ask that you do not submit any personal information to us. 

### Our Use of Your Personal Information

We use your name and other personal information to identify you as a Registered User in order to give you the full benefits of our Site and Services. 

For instance, we use your email address to send registration reminders, to notify you of Services or Site updates, and to send news and special offers. 

We use your credit card or other billing information to obtain payment for membership or other Services you have purchased. 

We provide you the opportunity to opt-out of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes when we ask for this information. By way of example only (and not limitation), if you register for an Account but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can generally indicate your preference on the registration form. If you no longer wish to receive news or promotional materials, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each news release or communication. 

### Control of Your Registered User Account

Access to your Registered User Account and the Registration Information is generally controlled by user name and password. It is your responsibility to keep your user name and password confidential at all times and you are solely responsible for all activity that occurs in your Account . If you become aware of any unauthorized use of your Account or Registration Information, or any other breach of security, you agree to notify DomainTools immediately. 

### Web Visit Information

DomainTools notes and saves information such as time of day, browser type, browser language, and IP address with each visit to our Site. That information is used to verify our records and to provide more relevant services to Users. For example, DomainTools may use your IP address or browser language to determine which language to use when showing search results or advertisements. 

### Cookies

Upon your first visit to the Site, DomainTools sends a "cookie" to your computer. A cookie is a piece of data that identifies you as a unique User. DomainTools uses cookies to improve the quality of our service and to better understand our User base. DomainTools does this by storing User preferences in cookies and by tracking User trends and patterns of how people search on our Site. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. Be aware, however, that some parts of the Services may not function properly if you refuse cookies. 

### Links to Other Sites

The Site may contain advertising and other links to third party websites at which personal information may be collected. You understand that, in such instances, DomainTools has no control over the information you provide and the collection and use of your personal information will be governed by the privacy policy applicable to that site. 

### Sharing of Information with Third Parties

DomainTools does not (and will not) sell or rent any of your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent. However, the following describes some of the ways that your personal information may be disclosed in the normal course of business as part of Services provided through our Site. 

_Advertisers._ We gather up data across numerous Registered User accounts and disclose such information in a non-personally identifiable manner to advertisers and other third parties for their marketing and promotional purposes. For such purposes, we do not disclose any information that we believe could be used to identify Users personally. DomainTools may receive a fee or other benefits for providing such information. 

_Affiliates for Our Operations._ We may use third parties ("affiliates") to facilitate or outsource one or more aspects of the Services that we provide to you (e.g., Transfer services related to payments, search technology, advertising provisions, and other services) and therefore we may provide some of your information directly to these affiliates. We may or may not hold an ownership interest in these affiliates. Affiliates are subject to confidentiality agreements with us and other legal restrictions that restrict or prohibit their use of the information we provide them for any other purpose except to facilitate the specific outsourced service, unless you have explicitly agreed or given your prior permission to them for additional uses. In some instances, the affiliate may collect information directly from you. In these cases, we will strive to tell you of the involvement of the affiliate, but what information you provide them will be up to you. 

_Agents and Business Entities._ We share some of our data, including personal information about you, with our affiliates, subsidiaries, and joint venturers that are committed to serving your online needs and providing related services throughout the world. For example, we use banking institutions to process all funds transfers related to our Services. These companies do not retain, share, store, or use personally identifiable information for purposes other than as related to their service or as otherwise required by law. To the extent that these entities have access to your information, they have assured us that they will treat it at least as protectively as they treat information they obtain from their other users. 

Our affiliates, subsidiaries, and joint venturers follow their own privacy practices that may be more or less protective of their users than DomainTools’s practices described in this document. DomainTools, its affiliates, subsidiaries, joint venturers, or any combination of such, will share some or all of your information with another business entity should we plan to merge with, or be acquired by, or obtain investment funds from that person or entity. 

_Legal Requests._ DomainTools cooperates with law enforcement authorities, as well as with other third parties, to enforce laws, intellectual property rights, and to prevent fraud. Although as noted below, we typically require a subpoena or similar legal document prior to doing so, we do reserve the right, in response to a verified request by law enforcement or other government officials relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity, we can, and you authorize us to, disclose your name, city, state, telephone number, email address, login name, access history, IP address, fraud complaints, and site use history, with or without a subpoena. 

Without restricting our rights to do so as noted above, as a general policy we will not disclose your personal information to law enforcement or other government officials without a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal procedure, except when we believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to protect our rights or to prevent imminent physical harm, financial loss or to report suspected past, present, or future illegal activity. Further, we can, and you authorize us to, disclose to a third party your information, including your name, street address, city, state, zip code, country, phone number, email, and company name, as we in our sole discretion believe necessary or appropriate in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other unlawful activity. 

### Security

DomainTools follows generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

Your information is stored on DomainTools' servers located in the United States and in European Union countries. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card or bank information) on our registration or order forms, we undertake to encrypt that information using secure socket layer or other similar technology (SSL). We treat data as an asset and strive to protect it from loss and unauthorized access. We employ many different security techniques to protect data from unauthorized access by users whether they are "inside" or "outside" DomainTools. You understand and agree that "perfect security "does not exist on the Internet or with any digital or physical data collection and retention systems. 

DomainTools personnel are trained appropriately regarding the application of privacy practices and the importance of protecting your information. 

### Contact Information

If you have a concern about your privacy, please contact us at http://www.domaintools.com/about/contact-us/
